<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<records xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.doaj.org/schemas/doajArticles.xsd">
    <record>
        <language>eng</language>
        <publisher>VU e-Publishing</publisher>
        <journalTitle>Stigma Research and Action</journalTitle>
        <eissn>2210-5174</eissn>
        <publicationDate>2011-02-28</publicationDate>
        <volume>1</volume>
        <issue>1</issue>
        <startPage>1</startPage>
        <endPage>2</endPage>
        <doi>10.5463/sra.v1i1.23</doi>
        <publisherRecordId>1</publisherRecordId>
        <title language="eng">The Need for Stigma Research and Action</title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <name>Heather Stuart</name>
                <email>heather.stuart@queensu.ca</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <affiliationsList>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="0">Queen’s University, Kingston, Ontario,</affiliationName>
        </affiliationsList>
        <abstract language="eng">&lt;p&gt;Stigma and discrimination affect the lives of people who are perceived as
            different from the norm in some important way—the physically or mentally disabled, those who are overweight
            or obese, those who suffer from infectious diseases ranging from leprosy to HIV/AIDS, as well as members of
            certain cultural and minority groups. While the exact mechanisms are unknown, the stigmatization process
            most certainly includes a complex array of personal, interpersonal, and structural components. Link and
            Phelan (2001) refer to this as a labyrinth of details that creates substantial social inequalities in life
            circumstances even when it is difficult for an individual to specify any single causal event. Multiple,
            mutually reinforcing mechanisms are used by dominant groups to maintain their pre-eminence. When one
            mechanism is weakened, another is strengthened. Over time the process becomes increasingly complex, subtle,
            and covert.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;10.5463/sra.v1i1.23&lt;/p&gt;
        </abstract>
        <fullTextUrl format="html">http://stigmaj.org/article/view/23</fullTextUrl>
        <keywords/>
    </record>
    <record>
        <language>eng</language>
        <publisher>VU e-Publishing</publisher>
        <journalTitle>Stigma Research and Action</journalTitle>
        <eissn>2210-5174</eissn>
        <publicationDate>2011-02-28</publicationDate>
        <volume>1</volume>
        <issue>1</issue>
        <startPage>3</startPage>
        <endPage>10</endPage>
        <doi>10.5463/sra.v1i1.11</doi>
        <publisherRecordId>2</publisherRecordId>
        <title language="eng">Stigma Related To HIV Among Community Health Workers In Chile</title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <name>Rosina Cianelli</name>
                <email>rcianelli@miami.edu</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Lilian Ferrer</name>
                <email>rcianelli@miami.edu</email>
                <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Kathleen F. Norr</name>
                <email>rcianelli@miami.edu</email>
                <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Linda McCreary</name>
                <email>rcianelli@miami.edu</email>
                <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Lisette Irarrázabal</name>
                <email>rcianelli@miami.edu</email>
                <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Margarita Bernales</name>
                <email>rcianelli@miami.edu</email>
                <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Sarah Miner</name>
                <email>rcianelli@miami.edu</email>
                <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <affiliationsList>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="0">University of Miami, Miami, FL</affiliationName>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="1"></affiliationName>
        </affiliationsList>
        <abstract language="eng">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose:&lt;/strong&gt; When healthcare workers have
            stigmatizing attitudes toward people living with HIV it may lead to discriminatory behavior that interferes
            with prevention, treatment, and care. This research examined the HIV-related stigmatizing attitudes reported
            by health workers in Santiago, Chile.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods:&lt;/strong&gt; The study used
            focus group data from the first phase of a larger study to develop and test a HIV prevention intervention
            for Chilean health workers. Ten focus groups were conducted with Health workers in two communities in
            Santiago, Chile. Content analysis was used to analyze the data. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results:
            &lt;/strong&gt;Two central themes emerged: Societal stigma and discrimination towards people living with HIV
            and healthcare system’s policies related to HIV. Both inaccurate fears of transmission among the general
            public and Chilean Health workers and societal prejudices against homosexuals contributed to stigmatization
            and discrimination.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions&lt;/strong&gt;: Health workers did not
            recognize their own stigmatizing attitudes or discriminatory behaviors, but their discussion indicated that
            these behaviors and attitudes did exist. Healthcare system issues identified included problems with
            confidentiality due to the desire to inform other health workers about client HIV status. Health workers
            must be sensitized to the current stigmatization and misinformation associated with HIV and its negative
            impacts on persons living with HIV and the general community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implications&lt;/strong&gt;:
            All clinical and non-clinical workers at community clinics need mandatory education for HIV prevention that
            focuses on changing attitudes as well as sharing knowledge. Also, the Chilean law protecting people living
            with HIV and the confidentiality of their medical care needs to be publicized, along with guidelines for its
            enactment in clinics and other health facilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;10.5463/sra.v1i1.11&lt;/p&gt;
        </abstract>
        <fullTextUrl format="html">http://stigmaj.org/article/view/11</fullTextUrl>
        <keywords>
            <keyword>Chile, community, health workers, HIV, stigma</keyword>
        </keywords>
    </record>
    <record>
        <language>eng</language>
        <publisher>VU e-Publishing</publisher>
        <journalTitle>Stigma Research and Action</journalTitle>
        <eissn>2210-5174</eissn>
        <publicationDate>2011-02-28</publicationDate>
        <volume>1</volume>
        <issue>1</issue>
        <startPage>11</startPage>
        <endPage>17</endPage>
        <doi>10.5463/sra.v1i1.10</doi>
        <publisherRecordId>3</publisherRecordId>
        <documentType>qualitative research</documentType>
        <title language="eng">Internalized stigma of mental illness in Tehran, Iran</title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <name>Helia Ghanean</name>
                <email>helia.ghanean@psychiat.umu.se</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Marzieh Nojomi</name>
                <email>helia.ghanean@psychiat.umu.se</email>
                <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Lars Jacobsson</name>
                <email>lars.jacobsson@psychiat.umu.se</email>
                <affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <affiliationsList>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="0">Umeå University, Umeå, Sweden and&#13;
                Iran University of Medical Sciences (IUMS), Tehran, Iran
            </affiliationName>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="1">Iran University of Medical Sciences (IUMS), Tehran</affiliationName>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="2">Umeå University, Umeå</affiliationName>
        </affiliationsList>
        <abstract language="eng">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: There are an increasing number of
            studies on the subjective experience of stigma amongst mentally ill persons but still few coming from low-
            and middle-income countries, and very few from Muslim countries. The objective of this study was to look
            into the experience of internalized stigma in mentally ill persons in Tehran, Iran. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;:
            A total of 138 patients with an affective disorder or schizophrenia from three psychiatric institutions in
            Tehran responded to the Internalized Stigma of Mental Illness Scale (ISMIS). This is a 29-item self-report
            questionnaire with good psychometric properties. An open-ended question about personal experiences of
            discrimination was included in the end of the questionnaire.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results:&lt;/strong&gt;
            The experience of stigma because of mental illnesses was high in this Iranian sample. The level of stigma
            was similar to studies from Europe that used the same questionnaire. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;:
            This is the first study of self-perceived stigma in mentally ill persons in Iran. Stigma is a reality even
            in an Islamic setting in spite of the teachings of the Koran and a rather well-developed mental health
            service. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implications&lt;/strong&gt;: These
            results call for actions to reduce the experience of stigma in mentally ill persons in Iran.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;10.5463/sra.v1i1.10&lt;/p&gt;
        </abstract>
        <fullTextUrl format="html">http://stigmaj.org/article/view/10</fullTextUrl>
        <keywords>
            <keyword>Internalized stigma, Iran, Islam, mental illness, perceived discrimination</keyword>
        </keywords>
    </record>
    <record>
        <language>eng</language>
        <publisher>VU e-Publishing</publisher>
        <journalTitle>Stigma Research and Action</journalTitle>
        <eissn>2210-5174</eissn>
        <publicationDate>2011-02-28</publicationDate>
        <volume>1</volume>
        <issue>1</issue>
        <startPage>18</startPage>
        <endPage>26</endPage>
        <doi>10.5463/sra.v1i1.12</doi>
        <publisherRecordId>4</publisherRecordId>
        <title language="eng">Implicit and Explicit Obesity Bias in Pre-adolescents and their Relations to Self-Reported
            Body Mass Index
        </title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <name>Weidong Li</name>
                <email>li.832@osu.edu</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Paul Rukavina</name>
                <email>paulrukavina@hotmail.com</email>
                <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <affiliationsList>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="0">The Ohio State University</affiliationName>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="1">Adelphi University</affiliationName>
        </affiliationsList>
        <abstract language="eng">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: This study examined negative attitudes
            toward overweight peers among pre-adolescents using different explicit and implicit measures and analyzed
            their relationships with self-reported Body Mass Index (BMI).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;:
            Two hundred and twenty-four 7th and 8th graders enrolled in physical education classes from an urban school
            served as participants in this study. Anti-Fat Attitudes Test, Implicit Association Test, and BMI were
            administered during their regular class time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;:
            Adolescents surveyed had moderately high implicit biases toward obese individuals in almost all areas.
            Partial weak correlations were observed between explicit and implicit bias. Participants who had lower BMI
            were likely to assign higher scores on the implicit smart/stupid and good/bad subscales, suggesting that
            thinner adolescents tend to be more implicitly biased.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions&lt;/strong&gt;:
            Results suggest that interventions to reduce bias may need to be comprehensive so that they can fully affect
            an individual’s implicit biases in all measured areas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;10.5463/sra.v1i1.12&lt;/p&gt;
        </abstract>
        <fullTextUrl format="html">http://stigmaj.org/article/view/12</fullTextUrl>
        <keywords>
            <keyword>weight stigma, obesity bias, BMI</keyword>
        </keywords>
    </record>
    <record>
        <language>eng</language>
        <publisher>VU e-Publishing</publisher>
        <journalTitle>Stigma Research and Action</journalTitle>
        <eissn>2210-5174</eissn>
        <publicationDate>2011-02-28</publicationDate>
        <volume>1</volume>
        <issue>1</issue>
        <startPage>27</startPage>
        <endPage>35</endPage>
        <doi>10.5463/sra.v1i1.16</doi>
        <publisherRecordId>5</publisherRecordId>
        <title language="eng">Chinese culture, homosexuality stigma, social support, and condom use: A path analytic
            model
        </title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <name>Hongjie Liu</name>
                <email>hliu@vcu.edu</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Tiejian Feng</name>
                <email>tiejian.feng@gmail.com</email>
                <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Toan Ha</name>
                <email>tha@vcu.edu</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Hui Liu</name>
                <email>lhxb1@163.com</email>
                <affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Yumao Cai</name>
                <email>caiyumao@hotmail.com</email>
                <affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Xiaoli Liu</name>
                <email>xiaoli@163.com</email>
                <affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Jian Li</name>
                <email>jli4@vcu.edu</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <affiliationsList>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="0">Virginia Commonwealth University</affiliationName>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="1">Shenzhen Center for Chronic Disease Control</affiliationName>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="2">China Center for HIV/AIDS Control and Prevention</affiliationName>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="3">Shenzhen Center for Chronic Disease Control and Prevention
            </affiliationName>
        </affiliationsList>
        <abstract language="eng">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: The objective of this study was to
            examine the interrelationships among individualism, collectivism, homosexuality-related stigma, social
            support, and condom use among Chinese men who have sex with men.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;:
            A cross-sectional study using the respondent-driven sampling approach was conducted among 351 eligible men
            who have sex with men in Shenzhen, China. Path analytic modeling was used to analyze the interrelationships.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;:
            The results of path analytic modeling document the following statistically significant associations: (1)
            higher levels of vertical collectivism were associated with higher levels of public homosexual stigma [β
            (standardized coefficient) = 0.12] and self homosexual stigma (β = 0.12); (2) higher levels of vertical
            individualism were associated with higher levels self homosexual stigma (β = 0.18); (3) higher levels of
            horizontal individualism were associated with higher levels of public homosexual stigma (β = 0.12); (4)
            higher levels of self homosexual stigma were associated with higher levels of social support from sexual
            partners (β = 0.12); and (5) lower levels of public homosexual stigma were associated with consistent condom
            use (β = -0.19).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions&lt;/strong&gt;: The findings enhance our
            understanding of how individualist and collectivist cultures influence the development of
            homosexuality-related stigma, which in turn may affect individuals’ decisions to engage in HIV-protective
            practices and seek social support. Accordingly, the development of HIV interventions for men who have sex
            with men in China should take the characteristics of Chinese culture into consideration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;10.5463/sra.v1i1.16&lt;/p&gt;
        </abstract>
        <fullTextUrl format="html">http://stigmaj.org/article/view/16</fullTextUrl>
        <keywords>
            <keyword>men who have sex with men, HIV/AIDS, individualism, collectivism</keyword>
        </keywords>
    </record>
    <record>
        <language>eng</language>
        <publisher>VU e-Publishing</publisher>
        <journalTitle>Stigma Research and Action</journalTitle>
        <eissn>2210-5174</eissn>
        <publicationDate>2011-02-28</publicationDate>
        <volume>1</volume>
        <issue>1</issue>
        <startPage>36</startPage>
        <endPage>43</endPage>
        <doi>10.5463/sra.v1i1.20</doi>
        <publisherRecordId>6</publisherRecordId>
        <title language="eng">Self and others: the differential impact of an anti-stigma programme</title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <name>Neil Quinn</name>
                <email>neil.quinn@strath.ac.uk</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Michael Smith</name>
                <email>michael.smith3@nhs.net</email>
                <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Susan Fleming</name>
                <email>susan.fleming@ggc.scot.nhs.uk</email>
                <affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Amanda Shulman</name>
                <email>amandashulman@yahoo.com</email>
                <affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Lee Knifton</name>
                <email>leeknifton@gmail.com</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <affiliationsList>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="0">University of Strathclyde</affiliationName>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="1">University of Glasgow</affiliationName>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="2">Greater Glasgow and Clyde NHS</affiliationName>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="3"></affiliationName>
        </affiliationsList>
        <abstract language="eng">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: We investigated whether respondents’
            first person views differed from their “third person” views reflecting their assessment of attitudes of
            other people. Secondly we examined whether first-person and third-person views changed following an
            anti-stigma workshop.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Method&lt;/strong&gt;: A repeated measures design was
            used to evaluate nine 6-hour workshops delivered to 87 employees of public and private sector organizations
            over five months. Questions measuring both first person (15 items) and third person (15 items) views were
            administered before and after the workshops.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;: At
            baseline, stigma scores were higher for third person views, reflecting higher levels of stigma. There was a
            reduction in stigma following the workshop for both first and third person views. The reduction in
            self-reported stigmatizing attitudes was greater when assessing “first person” compared to “third person”
            stigma.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;: The findings suggest that individuals
            typically consider themselves less stigmatizing than others. First person views were more sensitive to
            change following an anti-stigma intervention.&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;doi/10.5463/sra.v1i1.20&lt;/p&gt;
        </abstract>
        <fullTextUrl format="html">http://stigmaj.org/article/view/20</fullTextUrl>
        <keywords>
            <keyword>stigma, attitudes, discrimination, mental health, public education</keyword>
        </keywords>
    </record>
    <record>
        <language>eng</language>
        <publisher>VU e-Publishing</publisher>
        <journalTitle>Stigma Research and Action</journalTitle>
        <eissn>2210-5174</eissn>
        <publicationDate>2011-02-28</publicationDate>
        <volume>1</volume>
        <issue>1</issue>
        <startPage>44</startPage>
        <endPage>53</endPage>
        <doi>10.5463/sra.v1i1.17</doi>
        <publisherRecordId>7</publisherRecordId>
        <title language="eng">Changing Knowledge and Attitudes with a Middle School Mental Health Education Curriculum
        </title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <name>Otto F Wahl</name>
                <email>owahl@hartford.edu</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Janet Susin</name>
                <email>jasusin@optonline.net</email>
                <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Lorraine Kaplan</name>
                <email>lorkaplan@verizon.net</email>
                <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Amy Lax</name>
                <email>amylax@optonline.net</email>
                <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Dayna Zatina</name>
                <email>dayna.zatina@gmail.com</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <affiliationsList>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="0">University of Hartford</affiliationName>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="1">NAMI Queens/Nassau</affiliationName>
        </affiliationsList>
        <abstract language="eng">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: This research tested the effectiveness
            of a widely used mental health education curriculum in changing knowledge and attitudes about mental
            illness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Method&lt;/strong&gt;: Middle school students from four schools
            were provided the Breaking the Silence: Teaching the Next Generation About Mental Illness mental health
            instruction while students from other classes at the same schools received usual class instruction. Students
            completed questionnaires assessing knowledge, attitudes, and social distance preferences before, immediately
            after, and six weeks after the instruction was given.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;:
            Students given the Breaking the Silence instruction showed improvements in knowledge about mental illness,
            attitudes toward mental illness, and willingness to interact with people with mental illnesses. Students in
            the comparison classes showed no changes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions&lt;/strong&gt;:
            Breaking the Silence was an effective means of improving the knowledge and attitudes of middle school
            students about mental illness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implications&lt;/strong&gt;: An
            easy-to-administer and effective curriculum, Breaking the Silence is available to teachers and schools to
            help improve understanding and acceptance of people with mental illness. Such a curriculum, introduced
            during childhood and adolescence, may help to prevent the negative attitudes and misunderstanding that
            characterize adult perceptions of mental illness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;10.5463/sra.v1i1.17&lt;/p&gt;
        </abstract>
        <fullTextUrl format="html">http://stigmaj.org/article/view/17</fullTextUrl>
        <keywords>
            <keyword>Stigma reduction</keyword>
            <keyword>mental health education</keyword>
            <keyword>program effectiveness</keyword>
            <keyword>student attitudes</keyword>
            <keyword>Breaking the Silence curriculum</keyword>
        </keywords>
    </record>
    <record>
        <language>eng</language>
        <publisher>VU e-Publishing</publisher>
        <journalTitle>Stigma Research and Action</journalTitle>
        <eissn>2210-5174</eissn>
        <publicationDate>2011-02-28</publicationDate>
        <volume>1</volume>
        <issue>1</issue>
        <startPage>54</startPage>
        <endPage>59</endPage>
        <doi>10.5463/sra.v1i1.9</doi>
        <publisherRecordId>8</publisherRecordId>
        <documentType>quantitative study</documentType>
        <title language="eng">Prevalence of Internalized Stigma among Persons with Severe Mental Illness</title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <name>Michelle L. West</name>
                <email>pyanos@jjay.cuny.edu</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Philip T. Yanos</name>
                <email>pyanos@jjay.cuny.edu</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Stephen M. Smith</name>
                <email>pyanos@jjay.cuny.edu</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>David Roe</name>
                <email>droe@univ.haifa.ac.il</email>
                <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Paul H. Lysaker</name>
                <email>plysaker@iupui.edu</email>
                <affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <affiliationsList>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="0">John Jay College of Criminal Justice, New York</affiliationName>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="1">University of Haifa</affiliationName>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="2">Indiana University</affiliationName>
        </affiliationsList>
        <abstract language="eng">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: There is evidence that internalized
            stigma significantly impacts the lives of people with severe mental illness. Nevertheless, there is little
            data on the prevalence of clinically significant internalized stigma. This study investigated the current
            prevalence and demographic correlates of significantly elevated levels of internalized stigma in two samples
            of people with severe mental illness living in the community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Method&lt;/strong&gt;:
            A total of 144 people (79.9% males, 20.1% females) participated, completing a demographic form and the
            Internalized Stigma of Mental Illness scale.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;:
            Overall, 36% of the sample had elevated internalized stigma scores using a cutoff criterion. Participants in
            the middle of the age distribution had the highest scores, and there was a site difference. No other
            demographic variables studied were related to overall internalized stigma.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions&lt;/strong&gt;:
            We conclude that internalized stigma affects a relatively high percentage of people with severe mental
            illness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;10.5463/sra.v1i1.9&lt;/p&gt;
        </abstract>
        <fullTextUrl format="html">http://stigmaj.org/article/view/9</fullTextUrl>
        <keywords>
            <keyword>internalized stigma, self-stigma, severe mental illness, prevalence, Internalized Stigma of Mental
                Illness
            </keyword>
        </keywords>
    </record>
    <record>
        <language>eng</language>
        <publisher>VU e-Publishing</publisher>
        <journalTitle>Stigma Research and Action</journalTitle>
        <eissn>2210-5174</eissn>
        <publicationDate>2011-02-28</publicationDate>
        <volume>1</volume>
        <issue>1</issue>
        <startPage>60</startPage>
        <endPage>66</endPage>
        <doi>10.5463/sra.v1i1.3</doi>
        <publisherRecordId>9</publisherRecordId>
        <documentType>qualitative study</documentType>
        <title language="eng">Substance Abuse Stigma and Discrimination Among African American Male Substance Users
        </title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <name>Melanie C. Scott</name>
                <email>melanie.scott@yale.edu</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Otto F. Wahl</name>
                <email>owahl@harford.edu</email>
                <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <affiliationsList>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="0">Department of Psychiatry, Yale University School of Medicine
            </affiliationName>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="1">Graduate Institute of Professional Psychology, University of Hartford
            </affiliationName>
        </affiliationsList>
        <abstract language="eng">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: This qualitative study examined the
            experience, manifestations, and impact of racial discrimination and substance abuse stigma, also known as a
            double stigma, among 10 African-American male substance users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Method&lt;/strong&gt;:
            Interviews were audio-taped, transcribed, and analyzed for themes using Grounded Theory methodology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;:
            Racial discrimination and substance abuse stigma were common experiences. In terms of a double
            stigma,interviewees perceived that their substance use problems were viewed differently, and less favorably,
            than the substance related disorders of non-minority clients. Spirituality also was an important aspect of
            coping for a majority of interviewees.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions&lt;/strong&gt;: This
            qualitative approach utilizing Grounded Theory was successful in collecting and summarizing the narrative
            experiences of double stigma among African American male substance users. A double stigma experienced by
            African-American males with substance related disorders may cause potentially harmful effects on treatment
            engagement and success.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;10.5463/sra.v1i1.3&lt;/p&gt;
        </abstract>
        <fullTextUrl format="html">http://stigmaj.org/article/view/3</fullTextUrl>
        <keywords>
            <keyword>African-American, discrimination, grounded theory, qualitative, stigma, substance abuse</keyword>
        </keywords>
    </record>
    <record>
        <language>eng</language>
        <publisher>VU e-Publishing</publisher>
        <journalTitle>Stigma Research and Action</journalTitle>
        <eissn>2210-5174</eissn>
        <publicationDate>2011-02-28</publicationDate>
        <volume>1</volume>
        <issue>1</issue>
        <startPage>67</startPage>
        <endPage>72</endPage>
        <doi>10.5463/sra.v1i1.5</doi>
        <publisherRecordId>10</publisherRecordId>
        <title language="eng">Impact and Origin of Stigma and Discrimination in Schizophrenia: Patient Perceptions
        </title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <name>Amresh Shrivastava</name>
                <email>dr.amresh@gmail.com</email>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Megan Elizabeth Johnston</name>
                <email>megan.johnston@utoronto.ca</email>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Meghana Thakar</name>
                <email>meghana2711@yahoo.co.uk</email>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Siddhansh Shrivastava</name>
                <email>siddhansh@gmail.com</email>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Gopa Sarkhel</name>
                <email>gopamaitra@yahoo.com</email>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Iyer Sunita</name>
                <email>unisati@yahoo.com</email>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Shubhangi Parkar</name>
                <email>pshubhangi@gmail.com</email>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <abstract language="eng">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: Stigma and discrimination faced by
            patients with schizophrenia are the most important barriers to accessing care and can result in long
            treatment delays. Stigma is universal but the nature, source, and impact of stigma vary across cultures and
            regions. Thus, interventions need to be specific. This study assessed the perceptions of patients with
            schizophrenia regarding the stigma and discrimination they face in their lives. Main determinants and
            sources of stigma, as well as the nature of and forms of stigma were of interest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Method&lt;/strong&gt;:
            Opinions on various aspects of stigma were obtained using a semi-structured interview. One hundred patients
            with a diagnosis of schizophrenia, who were attending a psycho-education group in a hospital setting in
            Mumbai, India were surveyed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;: The stigma and
            discrimination linked to schizophrenia was found to have a significant impact on the lives of these
            individuals. From the patient perspective, a lack of knowledge, the nature of the illness itself, and
            behavioral symptoms were seen as the main reasons for stigma and discrimination. Common effects of stigma
            were low self-esteem and discrimination in family and work settings. Providing care and treatment was
            identified as the most common method of combating stigma. The availability of effective treatment was
            thought to be the most important method of reducing stigma, which will certainly aid in the access of mental
            health care for patients globally.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions&lt;/strong&gt;: The stigma
            associated with schizophrenia represents a challenge for effective mental health care. The solution for
            minimizing this stigma through anti-stigma programs is essential and necessitates the collection and
            analysis of complex information, particularly including patient perceptions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implications&lt;/strong&gt;:
            Dealing with stigma should be part of treatment and psycho-educational programs. Better treatment and
            rehabilitation for the illness and its symptoms is important, but so is educating members of the community,
            who are viewed as the primary source of stigma and discrimination.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;10.5463/sra.v1i1.5&lt;/p&gt;
        </abstract>
        <fullTextUrl format="html">http://stigmaj.org/article/view/5</fullTextUrl>
        <keywords/>
    </record>
    <record>
        <language>eng</language>
        <publisher>VU e-Publishing</publisher>
        <journalTitle>Stigma Research and Action</journalTitle>
        <eissn>2210-5174</eissn>
        <publicationDate>2011-02-28</publicationDate>
        <volume>1</volume>
        <issue>1</issue>
        <startPage>73</startPage>
        <endPage>75</endPage>
        <doi>10.5463/sra.v1i1.18</doi>
        <publisherRecordId>11</publisherRecordId>
        <title language="eng">Stigma</title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <name>Paul Jay Fink</name>
                <email>Pjayfink@aol.com</email>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <abstract language="eng">&lt;p&gt;When I read about the development of a new journal dealing with stigma, I got
            excited because it is an area I have been working in for over 30 years. I have carried around the
            announcement with me, determined to write a piece for submission. In the 1980s, I delivered a speech titled,
            The Enigma of Stigma (Fink, 1983) scores of times and ultimately Overcoming Stigma was the theme of the
            American Psychiatric Association&amp;rsquo;s Annual Meeting in 1989 when I was President. Surprisingly, we
            received over 100 submissions on the topic for the meeting, so there are a lot of psychiatrists and
            psychologists out there who still worry about the corrosive and destructive effect of stigma on the mental
            health of the nation. Rosalynn Carter has been an inspiration and has never given up in her quest to end
            stigma against the mentally ill and their caretakers. Unfortunately, the battle continues. The nay-sayers,
            the jokers, and the people who feel a need to ridicule those who are suffering from serious mental illnesses
            are still out there in large numbers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;10.5463/sra.v1i1.18&lt;/p&gt;
        </abstract>
        <fullTextUrl format="html">http://stigmaj.org/article/view/18</fullTextUrl>
        <keywords>
            <keyword>First account</keyword>
        </keywords>
    </record>
    <record>
        <language>eng</language>
        <publisher>VU e-Publishing</publisher>
        <journalTitle>Stigma Research and Action</journalTitle>
        <eissn>2210-5174</eissn>
        <publicationDate>2011-09-29</publicationDate>
        <volume>1</volume>
        <issue>2</issue>
        <startPage>1</startPage>
        <endPage>8</endPage>
        <doi>10.5463/sra.v1i2.27</doi>
        <publisherRecordId>12</publisherRecordId>
        <documentType>qualitative study</documentType>
        <title language="eng">Stigma as Perceived and Experienced by People with Mental Illness who receive Compulsory
            Community Treatment
        </title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <name>James David Livingston</name>
                <email>jlivingston@forensic.bc.ca</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Katherine R. Rossiter</name>
                <email>rossiter@sfu.ca</email>
                <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <affiliationsList>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="0">BC Mental Health &amp; Addiction Services</affiliationName>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="1">School of Criminology, Simon Fraser University</affiliationName>
        </affiliationsList>
        <abstract language="eng">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: The purpose of
            this study was to explore how stigma is perceived and experienced by people with mental illness who are
            legally required to use mental health services while living in the community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Method&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:
            Interviews were conducted with 91 people with mental illness who were receiving compulsory community mental
            health treatment in British Columbia, Canada. An inductive thematic analytic framework was used to identify
            predominant themes and recurring patterns in the qualitative data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:
            Participants’ narratives centered around six primary themes: (a) compulsory treatment; (b) feeling/being
            knocked down; (c) public (mis)understanding; (d) social identity/location; (e) social disadvantage; and (f)
            passing-managing-overcoming. Compulsory community treatment was entangled with a myriad of other
            stigma-producing factors associated with the direct effects of mental illness and social disadvantage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:
            Compulsory community mental health treatment is not the predominant issue that produces stigma among people
            with mental illness, but it may contribute to such experiences by creating situations where people are
            likely to feel powerless, devalued, and oppressed.&lt;/p&gt;
        </abstract>
        <fullTextUrl format="html">http://stigmaj.org/article/view/27</fullTextUrl>
        <keywords>
            <keyword>stigma, human rights</keyword>
        </keywords>
    </record>
    <record>
        <language>eng</language>
        <publisher>VU e-Publishing</publisher>
        <journalTitle>Stigma Research and Action</journalTitle>
        <eissn>2210-5174</eissn>
        <publicationDate>2011-09-29</publicationDate>
        <volume>1</volume>
        <issue>2</issue>
        <startPage>9</startPage>
        <endPage>21</endPage>
        <doi>10.5463/sra.v1i2.26</doi>
        <publisherRecordId>13</publisherRecordId>
        <documentType>implicit and explicit methods</documentType>
        <title language="eng">Reducing stigma toward seeking mental health treatment among adolescents</title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <name>Jena M Saporito</name>
                <email>Jena.Saporito@cherokeehealth.com</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>C Ryan</name>
                <email>bteachman@virginia.edu</email>
                <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Bethany Teachman</name>
                <email>bteachman@virginia.edu</email>
                <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <affiliationsList>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="0">University of Virginia and an Interdisciplinary Pre-Doctoral training
                Fellowship in Education Sciences
            </affiliationName>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="1">University of Virginia</affiliationName>
        </affiliationsList>
        <abstract language="eng">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: The current study examines the
            effectiveness of an intervention to reduce explicit and implicit measures of stigma toward mental illness
            and treatment-seeking, and increasing indicators of willingness to seek treatment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Method&lt;/strong&gt;:
            Adolescents were randomly assigned to the experimental (education about mental illness and treatment) or
            control (education about tobacco) intervention, involving psychoeducation and contact with an affected
            individual.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;: Results suggested the stigma
            intervention was effective at reducing explicit but not implicit measures of stigma. As hypothesized,
            participants receiving the experimental intervention reported less explicit stigma toward treatment. Also,
            individuals receiving the experimental intervention reported greater openness to personally seek treatment
            if they had also reported prior mental health treatment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions and
            Implications&lt;/strong&gt;: These findings support the potential for a brief educational intervention among
            adolescents to reduce negative attitudes toward mental health treatment, but raise questions about how to
            effectively address implicit stigma as well as the importance of translating stigma reduction into behavior
            changes.&lt;/p&gt;
        </abstract>
        <fullTextUrl format="html">http://stigmaj.org/article/view/26</fullTextUrl>
        <keywords>
            <keyword>: stigma, mental illness, treatment-seeking, implicit and explicit attitudes</keyword>
        </keywords>
    </record>
    <record>
        <language>eng</language>
        <publisher>VU e-Publishing</publisher>
        <journalTitle>Stigma Research and Action</journalTitle>
        <eissn>2210-5174</eissn>
        <publicationDate>2011-09-29</publicationDate>
        <volume>1</volume>
        <issue>2</issue>
        <startPage>22</startPage>
        <endPage>27</endPage>
        <doi>10.5463/sra.v1i2.22</doi>
        <publisherRecordId>14</publisherRecordId>
        <title language="eng">Adolescents and Psychosis: A Study on the Attitudes in a Northern Italian Town</title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <name>Chiara Buizza</name>
                <email>buizza@med.unibs.it</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Rosaria Pioli</name>
                <email>rpioli@fatebenefratelli.it</email>
                <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Laura Pedrini</name>
                <email>lpedrini@fatebenefratelli.it</email>
                <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Alberto Ghilardi</name>
                <email>ghilardi@med.unibs.it</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <affiliationsList>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="0">Faculty of Medicine and Surgery, University of Brescia</affiliationName>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="1">IRCCS "St. John of God" Fatebenefratelli</affiliationName>
        </affiliationsList>
        <abstract language="eng">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction: &lt;/strong&gt;scientific evidences show that
            psychotic disorders come to the treatment a few years after their onset, when the symptoms have stabilized.
            There are many factors responsible for this delay, including the role played by stigma, which often hinders
            an early identification of symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Materials and e methods: &lt;/strong&gt;a
            study was conducted in two high schools in a northern Italian town, through a questionnaire that assesses
            the attitudes towards people suffering from psychosis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;:
            408 students were enrolled in the study: 57.8% male and 42.2% female. Only 8.6% of the students believe that
            effective therapies for the treatment of people with psychosis exist, and only 16.4% states that most of
            them can recover or improve. 61.3% report that people with psychosis should be treated in hospitals for a
            long time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions&lt;/strong&gt;: the results show that students have
            negative attitudes towards people suffering from psychosis, in particular as regards the treatment. For this
            reason it’s important to promote public actions, of sensitization and information, in order to increase the
            knowledge about current model of community-based care for the treatment of these disorders and their
            possible positive outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
        </abstract>
        <fullTextUrl format="html">http://stigmaj.org/article/view/22</fullTextUrl>
        <keywords/>
    </record>
    <record>
        <language>eng</language>
        <publisher>VU e-Publishing</publisher>
        <journalTitle>Stigma Research and Action</journalTitle>
        <eissn>2210-5174</eissn>
        <publicationDate>2011-09-29</publicationDate>
        <volume>1</volume>
        <issue>2</issue>
        <startPage>34</startPage>
        <endPage>41</endPage>
        <doi>10.5463/sra.v1i2.25</doi>
        <publisherRecordId>15</publisherRecordId>
        <documentType>survey</documentType>
        <title language="eng">The ‘Human Face’ of Stigma in the Israeli Press: A Study or Representation</title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <name>Michal Soffer</name>
                <email>soffermi@bgu.ac.il</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <affiliationsList>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="0">Ben-Gurion University of the Negev</affiliationName>
        </affiliationsList>
        <abstract language="eng">&lt;h1&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p class="NormalWeb13"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt;
            This study examines the relationship between the degree of illness-related stigma and the representation of
            persons with severe physical illnesses in the press.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods:&lt;/strong&gt;
            A random sample of 478 published articles was drawn from three daily newspapers and two local newspapers in
            Israel over 12 months. The degree of illness-related stigma was measured using a scale developed for this
            study. Media representation was measured using content analysis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results:&lt;/strong&gt;
            Persons with ‘very stigmatized’ illnesses tended to be women, to be unattached, shown as members of a
            marginalized ethnicity, and as involved in deviant occupations. Additionally, they were described in bare
            detail, not named, portrayed as ‘dangerous others.'&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="NormalWeb13"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p
            class="NormalWeb13"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/strong&gt; People ‘very stigmatized’ illnesses were
            ‘symbolically annihilated,’ depicted as Others, and represented as an emblem of their illness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p
            class="NormalWeb13"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implications:&lt;/strong&gt; Changing media
            representations of persons with stigmatized illnesses is an essential step toward debunking illness-related
            stigma.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Key words&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;
            illness-related stigma, mass media, people with severe physical illnesses.&lt;/p&gt;
        </abstract>
        <fullTextUrl format="html">http://stigmaj.org/article/view/25</fullTextUrl>
        <keywords>
            <keyword>stigma, health conditions</keyword>
        </keywords>
    </record>
    <record>
        <language>eng</language>
        <publisher>VU e-Publishing</publisher>
        <journalTitle>Stigma Research and Action</journalTitle>
        <eissn>2210-5174</eissn>
        <publicationDate>2011-09-29</publicationDate>
        <volume>1</volume>
        <issue>2</issue>
        <startPage>42</startPage>
        <endPage>45</endPage>
        <doi>10.5463/sra.v1i2.29</doi>
        <publisherRecordId>16</publisherRecordId>
        <documentType>Opinion</documentType>
        <title language="eng">Stigma and HIV: time for a new paradigm?</title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <name>Ian Hodgson</name>
                <email>ian@ijhodgson.co.uk</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <affiliationsList>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="0">International HIV/AIDS Alliance</affiliationName>
        </affiliationsList>
        <abstract language="eng">&lt;p&gt;Stigmatising people with certain illnesses is a constant and damaging social
            behaviour. In particular, people living with HIV (PLHIV) have experienced discrimination and ostracisation
            since the beginning of the epidemic in the 1980s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Its prevalence has led in the HIV sector
            to a plethora of literature, toolkits, reports and conferences to the point where the demarcation between
            those who don’t stigmatise (the good – people who work in the HIV sector) and those who do (the bad –
            everyone else) is clearly established.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This paper proposes an alternative view (the
            ugly?), that stigma is a generic characteristic of the human condition, and to truly understand the
            phenomenon, we should look to ourselves and deconstruct our own tendencies to stigmatise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We
            may have more in common as a society than we like to admit.&lt;/p&gt;
        </abstract>
        <fullTextUrl format="html">http://stigmaj.org/article/view/29</fullTextUrl>
        <keywords>
            <keyword>HIV, stigma, culture, society, history</keyword>
        </keywords>
    </record>
    <record>
        <language>eng</language>
        <publisher>VU e-Publishing</publisher>
        <journalTitle>Stigma Research and Action</journalTitle>
        <eissn>2210-5174</eissn>
        <publicationDate>2011-09-29</publicationDate>
        <volume>1</volume>
        <issue>2</issue>
        <startPage>46</startPage>
        <endPage>47</endPage>
        <doi>10.5463/sra.v1i2.44</doi>
        <publisherRecordId>17</publisherRecordId>
        <documentType>Book</documentType>
        <title language="eng">P.W. Corrigan, D. Roe, H.W.H. Tsang (2011) Challenging the Stigma of Mental Illness.
            Lessons for Therapists and Advocates. Chichester, West Sussex: Wiley-Blackwell, 231 pages.
        </title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <name>Itzhak levav</name>
                <email>tuncho_levav@yahoo.com</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <affiliationsList>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="0">Ministry of Health</affiliationName>
        </affiliationsList>
        <abstract language="eng">&lt;p&gt;This is a small book – but exceedingly large in useful content.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This
            is just one positive comment of the many that could have been selected to open this review, on a helpful
            book where the delivery of well-presented and updated knowledge on the field of stigma and discrimination is
            for the sole purpose of prompting and guiding action. But, however appropriate this opening comment may be,
            it will be incomplete if the reviewer would not hastily add that the book is impregnated by a deep
            commitment to remove stigma, and more emphatically, discrimination in all walks of life, both ugly
            expressions of social injustice (cf. chapter 6).&lt;/p&gt;
        </abstract>
        <fullTextUrl format="html">http://stigmaj.org/article/view/44</fullTextUrl>
        <keywords>
            <keyword>Book review, Challenging mental illness Stigma, Therapists, Advocates</keyword>
        </keywords>
    </record>
    <record>
        <language>eng</language>
        <publisher>VU e-Publishing</publisher>
        <journalTitle>Stigma Research and Action</journalTitle>
        <eissn>2210-5174</eissn>
        <publicationDate>2011-09-29</publicationDate>
        <volume>1</volume>
        <issue>2</issue>
        <startPage>28</startPage>
        <endPage>33</endPage>
        <doi>10.5463/sra.v1i2.19</doi>
        <publisherRecordId>18</publisherRecordId>
        <title language="eng">Illness-Related Stigma in the Israeli Press: Media Coverage of Severe Physical Illnesses
        </title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <name>Michal Sofer</name>
                <email>soffer.michal@gmail.com</email>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <abstract language="eng">&lt;p style="margin: 0cm 0cm 0pt; line-height: 200%; mso-layout-grid-align: none;"
            class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small; font-family: Times New Roman;"&gt;Purpose:
            Illness-related stigma is argued to be largely shaped by the mass media. While scant research on the ways
            through which the media covers stigmatized illnesses does exist, there remains a need for a more
            generalizable model to predict the way any given physical illness would be covered in the media, and in
            particular, the ways that stigmatized illnesses would be covered. The aim of this exploratory study was to
            examine the relationship between the ascribed degree of disease stigma and its coverage in the media. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p
            style="margin: 0cm 0cm 0pt; line-height: 200%; mso-layout-grid-align: none;" class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span
            style="font-size: small;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"&gt;&lt;span
            style="mso-bidi-font-weight: bold;"&gt;Methods: &lt;/span&gt;We conducted a survey of 954 randomly sampled
            articles over a 12-month period from five newspapers in Israel. &lt;span style="mso-bidi-font-weight: bold;"&gt;The
            ascribed degree of disease stigma was measured via a questionnaire designed for the purpose of this study,
            which was completed by 26 &lt;/span&gt;experts. Two aspects of media coverage of physical illnesses were
            measured via content analysis: &lt;span style="mso-spacerun: yes;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em
            style="mso-bidi-font-style: normal;"&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; content is presented in the media and &lt;em
            style="mso-bidi-font-style: normal;"&gt;how&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span style="mso-bidi-font-style: italic;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;the
            content is covered. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin: 0cm 0cm 0pt; line-height:
            200%;" class="NormalWeb13"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small; font-family: Times New Roman;"&gt;Results:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span
            style="font-size: 10pt; color: black; line-height: 200%; font-family: Verdana;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span
            style="font-size: small;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Times New Roman;"&gt;We found that the more
            stigmatized the illness, the more coverage it received. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p
            style="margin: 0cm 0cm 0pt; line-height: 200%; mso-layout-grid-align: none;" class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span
            style="font-size: small; font-family: Times New Roman;"&gt;Very stigmatized illnesses tended to appear in
            weekend/holiday editions and on the front page of the newspaper, in articles which mentioned behavioral or
            lifestyle related risk factors as well as in articles that represented foreigners as placing others at risk
            for illness. Very stigmatized diseases tended to be covered as metaphors, i.e. used as symbols for foul
            social phenomena. These illnesses also tended to be described by military and apocalyptic metaphors.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p
            style="margin: 0cm 0cm 0pt; line-height: 200%;" class="NormalWeb13"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;
            font-family: Times New Roman;"&gt;Conclusions: Our findings imply that “very stigmatized” diseases are
            constructed as salient issues, presented as blame-able phenomena, and perceived as conveying major risk to
            the social and moral order. Social fears need to be understood and addressed when designing policy and,
            particularly, media campaigns, in order to eradicate illness-related stigma. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        </abstract>
        <fullTextUrl format="html">http://stigmaj.org/article/view/19</fullTextUrl>
        <keywords/>
    </record>
    <record>
        <language>eng</language>
        <publisher>VU e-Publishing</publisher>
        <journalTitle>Stigma Research and Action</journalTitle>
        <eissn>2210-5174</eissn>
        <publicationDate>2012-03-07</publicationDate>
        <volume>2</volume>
        <issue>2</issue>
        <doi>10.5463/sra.v1i3.28</doi>
        <publisherRecordId>19</publisherRecordId>
        <title language="eng">Is Stigma A Stigmatizing Word? A Political Question for Science</title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <name>Pat Corrigan</name>
                <email>corrigan@iit.edu</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Dror Ben-Zeev</name>
                <email>benzeevd@gmail.com</email>
                <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <affiliationsList>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="0">Illinois Institute of Technology</affiliationName>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="1">Dartmouth University</affiliationName>
        </affiliationsList>
        <abstract language="eng">&lt;p&gt;Asserting “stigma is a stigmatizing term” is a political statement, a position
            to which some social scientists may object. They may counter that allowing politics to bleed into an
            important scholarly question like this will undermine the quality of emerging answers. In this paper, we
            summarize what many sociologists and philosophers of scientific knowledge maintain; science and its methods
            are inextricably intertwined with political agenda. We demonstrate this by showing classic examples from
            astronomy as well as more relevant ones from medicine and psychiatry. Community based participatory research
            (CBPR) is an excellent vehicle for blending political opinion with scientific method so CBPR principles and
            practices are briefly reviewed, especially in terms of an anti-stigma research agenda. Ironically, we
            believe recognizing the limits of science for the stigma-is-a-stigmatizing-word question is by no means
            freeing for advocates. The community of stakeholders invested in this issue still need to deal with the
            political realities of their diversity and the challenge of developing consensus about stigma as a term and,
            more importantly, how to erase it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
        </abstract>
        <fullTextUrl format="html">http://stigmaj.org/article/view/28</fullTextUrl>
        <keywords>
            <keyword>Stigma, retire</keyword>
        </keywords>
    </record>
    <record>
        <language>eng</language>
        <publisher>VU e-Publishing</publisher>
        <journalTitle>Stigma Research and Action</journalTitle>
        <eissn>2210-5174</eissn>
        <publicationDate>2012-03-07</publicationDate>
        <volume>2</volume>
        <issue>2</issue>
        <doi>10.5463/sra.v1i3.46</doi>
        <publisherRecordId>20</publisherRecordId>
        <documentType>theoretical</documentType>
        <title language="eng">Reconceptualizing Stigma: Toward a Critical Anti-Oppression Paradigm</title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <name>Lynn C. Holley</name>
                <email>lholley@asu.edu</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Layne K. Stromwall</name>
                <email>stromwall@asu.edu</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Kathy E. Bashor</name>
                <email>Kathy.Bashor@azdhs.gov</email>
                <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <affiliationsList>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="0">Arizona State University School of Social Work</affiliationName>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="1">Arizona Department of Health Services</affiliationName>
        </affiliationsList>
        <abstract language="eng">&lt;p&gt;Theorists concerned with mental health prejudice and discrimination have
            conceptualized these problems as &lt;em&gt;stigma&lt;/em&gt;, typically defined as a labeling process that
            triggers stereotyping, followed by acts of discrimination that result in loss of status and reduced life
            options for people who are perceived to have mental illnesses (Goffman, 1963; Link &amp;amp; Phelan, 2001).
            Other stigma theorists have advocated for a social justice perspective (e.g., Corrigan, Watson, Byrne, &amp;amp;
            Davis, 2005; Perlin &amp;amp; Dorfman, 1993) or have recognized the need to consider meso- and macro-level
            factors (Pescosolido, Martin, Lang, &amp;amp; Olafsdottir, 2008) or structural arrangements (e.g., Corrigan,
            Markowitz, &amp;amp; Watson, 2004). Informed by critical theories and oppression literature, this paper
            offers theoretical arguments for replacing the current stigma model with a critical anti-oppression
            paradigm. This paradigm expands our lens to emphasize transforming the power dynamics inherent in
            system-level arrangements and structures that privilege those who are perceived as not having mental
            illnesses while disadvantaging others who are perceived to have mental illnesses. We conclude with
            implications of this paradigm for practice and research.&lt;/p&gt;
        </abstract>
        <fullTextUrl format="html">http://stigmaj.org/article/view/46</fullTextUrl>
        <keywords>
            <keyword>critical theories, privilege, critical consciousness, sanism, mental illnesses, discrimination
            </keyword>
        </keywords>
    </record>
    <record>
        <language>eng</language>
        <publisher>VU e-Publishing</publisher>
        <journalTitle>Stigma Research and Action</journalTitle>
        <eissn>2210-5174</eissn>
        <publicationDate>2012-03-07</publicationDate>
        <volume>2</volume>
        <issue>2</issue>
        <doi>10.5463/sra.v1i3.35</doi>
        <publisherRecordId>21</publisherRecordId>
        <documentType>systematic literature review</documentType>
        <title language="eng">The psychometric assessment of internalized stigma instruments: a systematic review
        </title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <name>Sharon Anne Maria Stevelink</name>
                <email>s.a.m.stevelink@vu.nl</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Ingeborg C Wu</name>
                <email>i.c.wu@vu.nl</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Carlijn G.N. Voorend</name>
                <email>carlijnvoorend@gmail.com</email>
                <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Wim H. van Brakel</name>
                <email>w.van.brakel@vu.nl</email>
                <affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <affiliationsList>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="0">VU University Amsterdam</affiliationName>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="1">Netherlands Leprosy Relief, Amsterdam, Netherlands</affiliationName>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="2">VU University Amsterdam&#13;
                Royal Tropical Institute Amsterdam
            </affiliationName>
        </affiliationsList>
        <abstract language="eng">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Objective&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt;
            Many instruments have been developed to assess stigma and related constructs across health conditions. The
            objective of this study was to provide an overview of the best validated instruments to measure internalized
            (or self-) stigma in health conditions where stigma plays a major role.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Method&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:
            A systematic literature review was conducted by searching relevant databases and by reviewing the
            bibliographies of relevant papers. Quantitative studies were included if the items used, or a sample of the
            instrument, were presented in the paper and if the studies focussed on the initial development of the
            instrument or a further validation. Health conditions included were HIV/AIDS, mental health, leprosy,
            asthma, epilepsy, cancer, obesity and tuberculosis. Psychometric properties of the included studies were
            assessed using several quality criteria: content validity, internal consistency, construct validity,
            criterion validity, reproducibility, responsiveness, floor and ceiling effects and interpretability. We
            rated the quality of the psychometric testing of the instruments using criteria proposed by Terwee et al.
            and the COSMIN consortium.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:
            Thirty-three papers were included of which 21 were identified as actual instrument development studies. Of
            the 21 instruments included only two instruments received three positive ratings on the quality criteria.
            Twelve  instruments were rated at least three times as indeterminate, especially for the criteria internal
            consistency and construct validity. This was due to insufficient samples sizes for factor analyses and
            hypotheses that were not formulated properly. At least one negative rating was given for five instruments.
            Content and construct validity as well as internal consistency were most often assessed, whereas agreement
            and responsiveness received least attention.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:
            This review attempted to rate the available instruments to measure internalized stigma using current
            standard quality criteria for testing psychometric properties. Only the Child Attitude Towards Illness Scale
            and the Internalized Stigma of Mental Illness received three positive ratings on the quality criteria. Based
            on the results, we conclude that the majority of the instruments needs further testing of their psychometric
            properties.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Implications:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;
            &lt;/em&gt;The need was identified for a simplified testing protocol to design an instrument development
            study, to assess certain psychometric properties and to specify the preferred statistical methods for
            testing these. In addition, researchers should be aware that re-validation of instruments is necessary once
            application will take place in cultures and study populations other than the one(s) the instrument was
            initially developed for.&lt;/p&gt;
        </abstract>
        <fullTextUrl format="html">http://stigmaj.org/article/view/35</fullTextUrl>
        <keywords>
            <keyword>assessment, health, internalized stigma, instruments, measurement, psychometric properties
            </keyword>
        </keywords>
    </record>
    <record>
        <language>eng</language>
        <publisher>VU e-Publishing</publisher>
        <journalTitle>Stigma Research and Action</journalTitle>
        <eissn>2210-5174</eissn>
        <publicationDate>2012-03-07</publicationDate>
        <volume>2</volume>
        <issue>2</issue>
        <doi>10.5463/sra.v1i3.41</doi>
        <publisherRecordId>22</publisherRecordId>
        <documentType>qualitative study</documentType>
        <title language="eng">Stigma Shrinks my Bubble: A Qualitative Study of Understandings and Experiences of Stigma
            and Bipolar Disorder
        </title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <name>Melinda Suto</name>
                <email>melinda.suto@ubc.ca</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <affiliationsList>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="0">University of British Columbia</affiliationName>
        </affiliationsList>
        <abstract language="eng">This study contributes to the
            stigma and bipolar disorder literature focused on understanding structural, social, and self-stigma
            experiences from the perspectives of individuals living with bipolar disorder and their family members.

            **Methods:**

            Community-based participatory research (CBPR) principles guided our engagement of individuals with bipolar disorder and community partners in the
            initiation, development, implementation, and reporting of this study. We collected data through focus groups with individuals living with bipolar disorder (3 groups)
            and family members (2 groups) during an annual bipolar disorder community engagement event. Thematic analysis was conducted as an iterative process and
            aided by several research team meetings.

            Three core themes emerged: (1) explicit and implicit exclusionary practices linked to structural stigma; (2) social stigma (e.g., "If my child had leukemia you would all be bringing me lasagna)" and; (3) the burden of self-stigma (e.g., "What’s wrong with
            me?"). These findings address issues arising in work, school, social, and health care settings
            that shape stigma phenomena. Parallels between the present findings and stigma experiences regarding other types of
            mental illnesses suggest considerable overlap. Individuals
            with bipolar disorder expressed hope for change that included (a) working with health care professionals who
            use a psychosocial rehabilitation approach and (b) implementing personal strategies for unloading the burden
            of self-stigma in their lives.

            **Implications:**

            The conceptualization of stigma as self, social and structural resonated well with the
            experiences and understandings of study participants. This conceptualization offers a bridge for
            communication between people with bipolar disorder, their families and health care practitioners and may be
            a useful framework for guiding efforts to reduce stigma. CBPR principles and lived experiences are crucial
            elements in stigma reduction endeavors.
        </abstract>
        <fullTextUrl format="html">http://stigmaj.org/article/view/41</fullTextUrl>
        <keywords>
            <keyword>community-based participatory research</keyword>
            <keyword>psychosocial factors</keyword>
            <keyword>mental health</keyword>
            <keyword>focus groups</keyword>
        </keywords>
    </record>
    <record>
        <language>eng</language>
        <publisher>VU e-Publishing</publisher>
        <journalTitle>Stigma Research and Action</journalTitle>
        <eissn>2210-5174</eissn>
        <publicationDate>2012-03-07</publicationDate>
        <volume>2</volume>
        <issue>2</issue>
        <doi>10.5463/sra.v1i3.45</doi>
        <publisherRecordId>23</publisherRecordId>
        <documentType>literature synthesis; narrative review</documentType>
        <title language="eng">Shifting our conceptualization of social inclusion</title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <name>Virginie Cobigo</name>
                <email>virginie.cobigo@gmail.com</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Hélène Ouellette-Kuntz</name>
                <email>helene.kuntz@queensu.ca</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Rosemary Lysaght</name>
                <email>lysaght@queensu.ca</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Lynn Martin</name>
                <email>Lynn.Martin@lakeheadu.ca</email>
                <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <affiliationsList>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="0">Queen's University</affiliationName>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="1">Lakehead University</affiliationName>
        </affiliationsList>
        <abstract language="eng">Objective. Social inclusion is a right, as well as a goal for community-based
            services and supports. Yet, there is a lack of consensus as to what constitutes social inclusion which means
            that there is no real way to determine and measure services effectiveness. This paper aims to identify
            current key components, definitions and conceptual approaches to social inclusion, and determine gaps in the
            scope and clarity of existing conceptualizations. **Method**. We conducted a synthesis review
            on the social inclusion of persons with intellectual and developmental disabilities. We extracted data
            relevant to the definition of social inclusion, its key principles and elements, as well as its main
            challenges. We adopted a narrative approach to synthesize the findings. **Results**. The main
            challenges in our understanding of social inclusion are: Social inclusion is at risk of being an ideology
            and may lead to ineffective and potentially harmful strategies; Social inclusion is still mainly defined as
            the acceptance and achievement of the dominant societal values and lifestyle which may lead to moralistic
            judgements; Social inclusion is often narrowly defined and measured as productivity and independent living,
            which is inappropriate for people with more severe disabilities; Social inclusion is often limited to the
            measure of one’s participation in community-based activities. **Conclusion and implications**.
            Shifting our understanding of social inclusion is essential. It means: Adopting a pro-active perspective
            that moves beyond theoretical discourse and leads to the identification of tools to improve social
            inclusion; Abandoning the moralistic perspective that tends to impose the view of the dominant group and
            leaning toward an approach respectful of individuals' expectations, choices and needs; Defining social
            inclusion from a developmental perspective where one's social inclusion improves with increased
            opportunities to interact with others and participate in activities; Including sense of belonging and
            well-being to our definition and measure of social inclusion.
        </abstract>
        <fullTextUrl format="html">http://stigmaj.org/article/view/45</fullTextUrl>
        <keywords>
            <keyword>Participation</keyword>
            <keyword>sense of belonging</keyword>
            <keyword>social justice</keyword>
            <keyword>discrimination</keyword>
            <keyword>social exclusion</keyword>
            <keyword>integration</keyword>
        </keywords>
    </record>
    <record>
        <language>eng</language>
        <publisher>VU e-Publishing</publisher>
        <journalTitle>Stigma Research and Action</journalTitle>
        <eissn>2210-5174</eissn>
        <publicationDate>2012-03-07</publicationDate>
        <volume>2</volume>
        <issue>2</issue>
        <doi>10.5463/sra.v1i3.48</doi>
        <publisherRecordId>24</publisherRecordId>
        <documentType>qualitative study</documentType>
        <title language="eng">The stigma of mental illness in Sri Lanka: the perspectives of community mental health
            workers
        </title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <name>Namali Samarasekara</name>
                <email>namalisamarasekara@gmail.com</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Matthew Lloyd Millins Davies</name>
                <email>daviesmatthew198@gmail.com</email>
                <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
            </author>
            <author>
                <name>Sisira Siribaddana</name>
                <email>nipuna@stmail.lk</email>
                <affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <affiliationsList>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="0">University of Leeds, UK</affiliationName>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="1">None</affiliationName>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="2">Rajarata University of Sri Lanka.&#13;
                Institute for Research &amp; Development, Sri Lanka.
            </affiliationName>
        </affiliationsList>
        <abstract language="eng">While the prevalence of mental illness is increasing, stigma associated with mental illness in Sri
            Lanka remains unexplored. **Aims** To gain an understanding of how stigma associated with mental illness exists in Sri Lanka, from the
            perspectives of community mental health workers (CMHWs). Furthermore, to explore their views on how any
            arising issues regarding stigma may be tackled in the future. **Methods** Purposive and snowball
            sampling methods were used to recruit community mental health workers for this small qualitative study. 
            Nine semi-structured interviews were conducted, using an interview guide designed by the first author.  The
            data was analysed using the ‘thematic framework’ approach **Results** Stigma is associated with the
            family unit; there is strong faith in traditional beliefs and healers; and negative attitudes and behaviours
            exist regarding mental illness.  CMHWs are influenced by poor health seeking behaviours and low
            prioritisation of mental health services in the country.  CMHWs can contribute to reducing stigma by
            increasing awareness of mental illness in various ways but also believe that increasing availability of
            services within Sri Lanka is key in reducing stigma. **Conclusions** This study provides insight into how stigma
            exists specifically in Sri Lankan communities and influences the work of CMHWs.  Many findings reinforce
            existing international health literature and thus convey that stigma is an important issue that must be
            tackled globally.
        </abstract>
        <fullTextUrl format="html">http://stigmaj.org/article/view/48</fullTextUrl>
        <keywords>
            <keyword>stigma</keyword>
            <keyword>health conditions</keyword>
        </keywords>
    </record>
    <record>
        <language>eng</language>
        <publisher>VU e-Publishing</publisher>
        <journalTitle>Stigma Research and Action</journalTitle>
        <eissn>2210-5174</eissn>
        <publicationDate>2012-03-07</publicationDate>
        <volume>2</volume>
        <issue>2</issue>
        <doi>10.5463/sra.v1i3.57</doi>
        <publisherRecordId>26</publisherRecordId>
        <title language="eng">Is it Time to Retire the Term Stigma?</title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <name>Amir Tal</name>
                <email>amir.t.tl@gmail.com</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <affiliationsList>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="0">University of Haifa, Israel</affiliationName>
        </affiliationsList>
        <abstract language="eng">&lt;p&gt;The term &lt;em&gt;stigma&lt;/em&gt; has undergone a number of re
            conceptualizations since it was first popularized by Goffman (1963) to refer to a mark of shame.  Since that
            time, the term has become common parlance to refer to socially undesirable conditions or affiliations. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The
            term ‘stigma’ has been used throughout the academic literature to refer to a wide range of social and
            psychological processes ranging from cognitive and attitudinal processes (Corrigan, Markowitz, Watson,
            Rowan, &amp;amp; Kubiak, 2003) to the structural elements that create and maintain social inequity and
            oppression (Link &amp;amp; Phelan, 2001).  However, not everyone is comfortable with the term &lt;em&gt;stigma
            &lt;/em&gt;or its connotations.  Critics have argued that it places a heavy focus on the characteristics of
            the stigmatized and not enough focus on the social and structural mechanisms that create and maintain
            discrimination (Everett, 2004).  Recently, several governmental and non-governmental organizations have
            called to retire the term stigma, instead favouring terms such as discrimination or social oppression. 
            Following these voices, &lt;em&gt;Stigma Research and Action&lt;/em&gt; called for papers debating this
            issue.  In this issue we present four commentaries that address this debate from different perspectives.  We
            hope that they will provoke thought and discussion. &lt;/p&gt;
        </abstract>
        <fullTextUrl format="html">http://stigmaj.org/article/view/57</fullTextUrl>
        <keywords>
            <keyword>Stigma, retire</keyword>
        </keywords>
    </record>
    <record>
        <language>eng</language>
        <publisher>VU e-Publishing</publisher>
        <journalTitle>Stigma Research and Action</journalTitle>
        <eissn>2210-5174</eissn>
        <publicationDate>2012-03-07</publicationDate>
        <volume>2</volume>
        <issue>2</issue>
        <doi>10.5463/sra.v1i3.58</doi>
        <publisherRecordId>27</publisherRecordId>
        <title language="eng">What’s In a Name?</title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <name>Bill George</name>
                <email>bill.george@planet.nl</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <affiliationsList>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="0">Coordinator, Anoiksis&#13;
                International Relations.
            </affiliationName>
        </affiliationsList>
        <abstract language="eng">‘What’s in a name? This is an
            open letter about a new name for schizophrenia in the DSM-5. Anoiksis, the Dutch patient society of and for people with a susceptibility to
            psychoses or schizophrenia, has lobbied the American Psychiatric
            Association for a new name for schizophrenia. The most recent suggestion — Bleuler’s Syndrome — is intended to do justice also to the negative and
            cognitive symptoms in the syndrome. This appears to correspond in part with the ideas of the chair of the
            appropriate American Psychiatric Association’s Work Group. The issue now is to gain support from the international
            mental health community.
        </abstract>
        <fullTextUrl format="html">http://stigmaj.org/article/view/58</fullTextUrl>
        <keywords>
            <keyword>schizophrenia,</keyword>
        </keywords>
    </record>
    <record>
        <language>eng</language>
        <publisher>VU e-Publishing</publisher>
        <journalTitle>Stigma Research and Action</journalTitle>
        <eissn>2210-5174</eissn>
        <publicationDate>2012-03-07</publicationDate>
        <volume>2</volume>
        <issue>2</issue>
        <doi>10.5463/sra.v1i3.60</doi>
        <publisherRecordId>29</publisherRecordId>
        <title language="eng">The Implications of Stigma for Institutionalized Violence</title>
        <authors>
            <author>
                <name>Cameron Ross McCordic</name>
                <email>cmccordi@uoguelph.ca</email>
                <affiliationId>0</affiliationId>
            </author>
        </authors>
        <affiliationsList>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="0">School of Environmental&#13;
                Design and Rural Development, University of Guelph, 50&#13;
                Stone Road East, Guelph, Ontario,
            </affiliationName>
        </affiliationsList>
        <abstract language="eng">The retirement of the stigma term is currently up for debate among advocacy groups.
            This debate questions the relevance and utility of the term for the conceptualization of discriminatory
            treatment against individuals who deviate from some societal norm. In Goffman’s (1963) seminal
            conceptualization of stigma, he described how stigma can be used to demonstrate an individual’s disqualified
            humanity. Further research has suggested that stigma can be used both to represent the disqualification of
            an individual’s humanity and to create humanity disqualification by inciting discrimination. While
            discrimination is a common result of stigma, there has been little discussion in academia regarding the use
            of stigma to promote the discrimination of certain groups or individuals by propagating prejudicial
            ideologies. This discrimination has implications for the justification and sanctioning of violence by
            institutions of power. Due to the fact that this is an area of stigma research which is largely
            uninvestigated, it would be premature to retire the stigma term without fully understanding its
            implications. This article will examine the implications of stigma for state sanctioned violence and review
            the limitations of this subject as a research topic.
        </abstract>
        <fullTextUrl format="html">http://stigmaj.org/article/view/60</fullTextUrl>
        <keywords>
            <keyword>stigma, discrimination, institutionalized violence</keyword>
        </keywords>
    </record>
</records>
